Guide to the William Goyen Papers, 1937-1978 MS 360
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
William Goyen papers
1937-1978
bulk
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Goyen, William
MS 360
6.25 Linear Feet (13 boxes)
The William Goyen papers consist of correspondence, manuscripts and notes, serial publications, reviews and publicity, and proofs and galleys.
Biographical Note
Charles William Goyen, author, editor, and teacher, was born in Trinity, Texas, on April 24, 1915 and moved with his family to Houston at the age of eight. He received B.A. and M.A. degrees from Rice University (then Institute) in 1937 and 1939, respectively. After teaching for one year at the University of Houston, he left to serve in the U.S. Navy during World War II. Returning after five years, he left Houston to pursue his work as a writer, residing at various times in New Mexico, Europe, New York, and California. His East Texas origins, however, were to have an enduring influence on the speech patterns and cultural characteristics reflected in his writings.
His first novel, House of Breath, was published to critical acclaim in 1950. Subsequent publications included the novels In a Farther Country (1955), The Fair Sister (1963), and Come the Restorer (1974); Selected Writings (1974); short story collections Ghost and Flesh (1952), The Faces of Blood Kindred (1960) and The Collected Stories (1975); the non-fiction A Book of Jesus (1973); and plays The House of Breath (1956), The Diamond Rattler (1960), Christy (1964), House of Breath Black/White (1971), and Aimee (1973). He also created lyrics for the film Left-Handed Gun (1958) and served as translator for The Lazy Ones by Egyptian author Albert Cossery.
In addition to being a writer, he was instructor of English at the New School for Social Research in New York City, 1955-60; Associate in English at Columbia University, 1964-66; senior editor in the trade department at McGraw Hill, 1966-71; and visiting Professor of English at Brown University, 1973. He married the actress Doris Roberts in 1963.
Among awards he received were music awards for words and music from the American Society of Composers, Authors, and Publishers (A.S.C.A.P.) in 1964, 1965, 1968, 1970, and 1971; an award from the Texas Institute of Arts and Letters, 1950; and the Distinguished Alumnus Award from Rice University in 1977. He was a Guggenheim fellow in 1950 and 1952 and a Ford Foundation grantee in 1963-64. He died in Los Angeles of leukemia in August 1983, two months before his novel Arcadio was published. Since then a number of his other late works have been edited and published.
Scope and Contents
The William Goyen papers are organized in five general categories: correspondence; manuscripts and notes; serial publications; reviews and publicity; and proofs and galleys. Boxes 1-4 contain correspondence, including correspondence from Goyen to William Hart (1937-1973); and correspondence from Goyen to his family (1940-1963), Boxes 2-4, and one folder of photographs, one folder of "family ephemera" such as newsclippings.
Boxes 5-10 contain notes, correspondence, and drafts for five of Goyen's major works, as follows: The House of Breath (Boxes 5-6); Ghost and Flesh (Box 7); In a Farther Country (Box 8); The Faces of Blood Kindred (Box 9); and The Fair Sister (Box 10). Serial Publications (1947-1978) are in Box 11; Reviews and Publicity are found in Box 12; and Box 13 includes Proofs and Galleys for The Collected Stories of William Goyen, Precious Door, Nine Poems, and A Book of Jesus.
Access Restriction
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Acquisition Information
The William Goyen Papers were received between 1961 and 1980 as gifts from Charles and Mary Alice Hamilton (manuscripts, notes, and galley proofs of five of Goyen's works); William Goyen (a deposit of his own collection of personal letters, mostly to his parents); and William M. Hart (letters written to him by Goyen, 1937-1951). In addition, Patrice Repusseau contributed a copy of his Master of Arts dissertation, An Approach to William Goyen's The House of Breath (Institut d'Anglais Charles V, Universite Paris VII, Paris, 1971).
Related Material
Additional information about William Goyen is available in an Information File under his name in the Woodson Research Center in the Fondren Library of Rice University.
In addition, the Special Collections department at the University of Houston's Anderson Library, and the Harry Ransom Humanities Research Center at the University of Texas at Austin also have significant collections of Goyen material.
Index Terms
Subjects
American literature -- 20th century; Authors
Subjects (Persons)
Goyen, William; Leger, Zoe; Hart, William M.; Goyen family
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Correspondence from Goyen to William Hart, 1937-1973; (171 items)
    - from Houston, signed (sob sister), Feb. 25, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - from Houston signed (Plato), March 3, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Waiting for Lefty, Odets play presented by Rice Dramatic Club, Mar. 23-24, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - from Houston signed (B.), March 31, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - from Houston signed (Willie), April 19, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - from Houston signed (Wil), April 26, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      General note
      w/ enclosures: Piece Written in a Drunken Stupor, Song for Alley-cats
    - from Houston? signed (W.G.), June 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - signed (W.G.), Oct. 16, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Friday night, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - from Houston signed (Billy), Jan. 14, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - from Houston signed (Billy G.), Feb. 6, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - from Houston signed (B.G.), May 14, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - (Sat. night) from New Braunfels, Sept. 1938 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - (Sun. night) from New Braunfels, Sept. 1938 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - (Mon. noon) from New Braunfels signed (Billy), Sept. 12, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      w/ 3 pp. enclosures
    - Christmas signed (B.G.), 1938 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Poems: Portent, Last Lines to S, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - signed (B), 1939 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Invitation to Rice Institute Commencement: Goyen -- Master of Arts, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Christmas signed (W.G.), 1939 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - from St. Louis signed (B), Sept. 18, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - from Houston signed (Billy), June 20, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - A Letter to Mr. Archibald MacLeish After Reading The Irresponsibles, June 1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - from Iowa City signed (Ulysses), Sept. 22, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - from Houston signed (B), Nov. 18, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - from Houston signed (B), July 1941 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from Houston signed (B), March 12, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      accompanying poetry
    - from Notre Dame signed (Billy), July 10, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from Notre Dame U. signed (Billy), August 2, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from New York signed (Billy), August 30, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from New York signed (Billy), Oct. 7, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from New York signed (Billy), Oct. 8, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from New York signed (Billy), Nov. 17, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from New York signed (Billy), Nov. 30, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from Balboa signed (Billy), Dec. 30, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from Balboa signed (Billy), Jan. 11, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from Balboa signed (Billy), Jan. 27, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from Balboa signed (Billy), Feb. 7, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from Balboa signed (Ulysses en mer), Feb. 11, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from Bremerton, Wash. signed (Billy), March 7, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from Bremerton, Wash. signed (Billy), March 27, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from Bremerton, Wash. signed (Billy), May 4, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      w/ 4pp TMs
    - signed (Billy), May 14, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - signed (Billy), June 1, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - signed (B), June 20, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from Bremerton, Wash. signed (Billy), June 29, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - A Tale of Simon (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from USS Casablanca, San Francisco signed (Billy), July 30, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from USS Casablanca signed (Billy), Aug. 16, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from USS Casablanca signed (Billy), Sept. 2, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from USS Casablanca signed (Billy), Sept. 14, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from USS Casablanca signed (Billy), Oct. 1, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from USS Casablanca signed (Billy), Nov. 3, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from USS Casablanca signed (Billy), Jan. 3, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from USS Casablanca signed (Billy), Feb. 22, 1944
      at sea
    - from USS Casablanca signed (Billy), Mar. 29, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - The Wind at Sewanto (C.W. Goyen), June 1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from Houston signed (Billy), July 23, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from USS Casablanca signed (Billy), Sept. 26, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from USS Casablanca signed (Billy), Dec. 1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from USS Casablanca signed (Bill), March 31, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from USS Casablanca signed (Billy), Sept. 22, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from Oakland, Ca. signed (Billy), Sept. 29, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from Hotel Jackson/Medford, Oregon signed (Bill), Oct. 11, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from Medford, Oregon signed (Billy), Oct. 16, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from Medford, Oregon signed (Billy), Oct. 19, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - from Medford, Oregon signed (Billy), Nov. 16, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Apostrophe to the Body, 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - A Prayer, 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Houston, to Prof. R.F.Arragon signed (William Goyen), Jan. 16, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Albuquerque signed (Billy), Mar. 1, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Santa Fe, N.M. signed (Billy), Mar. 4, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Taos, N.M. signed (Billy), Apr. 5, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Taos, N.M. signed (Billy), Apr. 29,May 4, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Taos, N.M. signed (Billy), June 8, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Taos, N.M. signed (Billy), June 19, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Taos, N.M. signed (Billy), July 15, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Taos, N.M. signed (Billy), August 24, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Taos, N.M. signed (Billy), Sept. 3, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Taos, N.M. signed (Billy), Nov. 1, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Taos, N.M. signed (Billy), Nov. 19, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      w/TL from Walt and ANS (B)
    - Dec. 1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Taos signed (Billy), Jan. 22, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Taos signed (Billy), March 14, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Taos signed (Billy), March 23, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      w/TNS from Walt
    - from Taos, July 8, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Napa, Cal. signed (Billy), Nov. 10, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Napa, Cal. signed (Billy), Jan. 12, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Dallas, Tx. signed (Billy), Mar. 19, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Dallas, Tx. signed (Billy), Mar. 24, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Taos signed (Billy), Apr. 29, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Taos signed (Billy), May 26, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Taos signed (Billy), June 3, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Taos signed (Billy), June 19, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Taos signed (Billy), June 30, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Taos signed (Billy), Aug. 31, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Portland, Ore. signed (Billy), Dec. 8, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Portland, Ore. signed (Billy), Jan. 16, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Portland, Ore. signed (Billy), Jan. 31, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Portland, Ore. signed (Billy), Feb. 20, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Portland, Ore. signed (Billy), May 19, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Taos signed (Billy), July 3, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Taos signed (Billy), July 15, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from London signed (Billy), Oct. 29, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from London signed (Billy), Nov. 21, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from Rome signed (Billy), Dec. 20, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Dec. 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - from New York signed (Billy), Apr. 8, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - from New York signed (Billy), Apr. 25, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - from New York signed (Billy), June 27, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - from New York signed (Billy), July 10, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - from New York signed (Billy), Aug. 20, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      w/book reviews
    - from New York signed (Billy), Sept. 20, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - from Chicago signed (Billy), Nov. 6, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - from Chicago signed (Billy), Dec. 29, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - from Saratoga Springs signed (Billy), Feb. 4, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - from Saratoga Springs signed (Billy), Feb. 27, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - from Houston signed (Billy), May 30, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      to Dorothy
    - June 5, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper clipping (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - from New York signed (Billy), Dec. 23, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Telegram from New York, Jan. 18, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - from New York signed (Billy), Jan. 20, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - from New York signed (Billy), Feb. 1, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - from New York signed (Billy), Feb. 10, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - from New York signed (Billy), Feb. 29, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - from New York signed (Billy), Apr. 9, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - from New York signed (Billy), Apr. 23, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - from New York signed (Billy), Oct. 19, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - from New York signed (Billy), Nov. 2, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Christmas, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      from Walter
    - May 10, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - from El Prado, NM signed (Billy), Aug. 5, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - from Italy signed (Billy), June 5, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - from Italy signed (Billy), June 16, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - from El Prado, NM signed (Billy), Oct. 10, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - from New York signed (Billy), Mar. 4, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Christmas from New York signed (Billy), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - from Fire Island,NY signed (Billy), July 23, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - from New York signed (Billy), July 10, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - from New York signed (Billy), Sept. 26, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      deals w/ Rice & donation of letters
    - from New York signed (Billy), May 17, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      deals w/ visit to Rice
    - from New York signed (Billy), July 11, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      deals w/ housing of mss at Rice
    - [carbon] from New York, June 7, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - [carbon] from NY signed (Billy), Aug. 30, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - from New York signed (Billy), May 3, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - from New York signed (Billy), June 3, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Recording of Apostrophe to the Body and A Prayer. (Box 1, Folder 9)
      (See folder 6)
  - Correspondence with Zoe Leger
    - from Port Isabel, Texas, Feb. 24, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - from Taos, NM, Apr. 17, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - from Taos, NM, Apr. 24, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - from Taos, NM, May 8, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - from Taos, NM, June 1, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - from Taos, NM, June 9, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - from Taos, NM, June 15, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - from Taos, NM, July 2, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - from Taos, NM, July 31, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - from Portland, Oregon, Dec. 5, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - from Portland, Oregon, Feb. 4, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - from Portland, Oregon, Feb. 25, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - from Portland, Oregon, May 4, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - from New York, NY, Apr. 16, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - from New York, NY, Oct. 22, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - from New York, NY, Feb. 8, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Photographs (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence from Goyen to his family, 1940-1943; (161 items)
    (all signed Bill or Billy)
    - To mother from St. Louis, Sept. 18, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - mother from Iowa City, Sept. 19, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - parents from San Diego, June 2, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - parents from Chicago, July 5, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - parents from Notre Dame, Indiana, July 7, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - family from Notre Dame, Indiana, July 8, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - mother from Notre Dame, Indiana, July 9, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - family from Notre Dame, Indiana, July 11, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - parents from Notre Dame, Indiana, July 12, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - mother from Notre Dame, Indiana, July 13, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - father from Notre Dame, Indiana, July 14, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - mother from Notre Dame, Indiana, July 16, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - mother from Notre Dame, Indiana, July 16, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - mother from Notre Dame, Indiana, July 20, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - mother from Notre Dame, Indiana, July 26, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - mother from Notre Dame, Indiana, July 29, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - parents from Notre Dame, Aug. 1, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - mother from Notre Dame, Aug. 3, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - family from Notre Dame, Aug. 4, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - family from Notre Dame, Aug. 8, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - mother from Notre Dame, Aug. 9, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - mother from Notre Dame, Aug. 11, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - mother from Notre Dame, Aug. 18, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Em from Notre Dame, Aug. 21, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - mother from New York, NY, Aug. 27, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Telegram to mother from New York, NY, Aug. 27, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - mother from New York, NY, Aug. 28, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - mother from New York, NY, Aug. 30, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - mother from New York, NY, Sept. 1, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - mother from New York, NY, Sept. 3, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - mother from New York, NY, Sept. 5, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - father from New York, NY, Sept. 8, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - mother from New York, Sept. 8, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Em (mother) from New York, Sept. 10, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - mother from New York, Sept. 13, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - family from New York, Sept. 15, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - mother from New York, Sept. 17, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - mother from New York, Sept. 21, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - mother from New York, Sept. 23, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - mother from New York, Sept. 28, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      w/ enclosure
    - family from New York, Sept. 29, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - mother from New York, Oct. 2, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - mother from New York, Oct. 5, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - mother from New York, Oct. 8, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - mother from New York, Oct. 13, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - mother from New York, Oct. 17, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - mother from New York, Oct. 20, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - mother from New York, Oct. 23, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - mother from New York, Oct. 27, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - father from New York, Oct. 27, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - mother from New York, Nov. 4, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - mother from New York, Nov. 4, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - mother from New York, Nov. 10, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - father from New York, Nov. 13, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - father from New York, Nov. 17, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - parents from New York, Nov. 24, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - announcement of Goyen's class commissioning on, Dec. 2, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - mother from Texarkana, Arkansas, Dec. 7, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - mother from Norfolk, Virginia, Dec. 9, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - mother from Norfolk, Virginia, Dec. 12, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - father from Norfolk, Virginia, Dec. 12, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - mother from Norfolk, Virginia, Dec. 14, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - family from Norfolk, Virginia, Dec. 24, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - mother from Balboa, Canal Zone, Dec. 27, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - parents from Balboa, Canal Zone, Dec. 28, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - mother from Balboa, Canal Zone, Dec. 30, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - parents New Year's Eve, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - mother from Balboa, Canal Zone, Jan. 4, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Em from Balboa, Canal Zone, Jan. 4, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - father from Balboa, Canal Zone, Jan. 6, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - mother from Balboa, Canal Zone, Jan. 9, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - mother from Balboa, Canal Zone, Jan. 9, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - father from Balboa, Canal Zone, Jan. 10, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Em from Balboa, Canal Zone, Jan. 12, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - mother from Balboa, Canal Zone, Jan. 14, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - father from Balboa, Canal Zone, Jan. 16, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - mother from Balboa, Canal Zone, Jan. 17, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Em from Balboa, Canal Zone, Jan. 19, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - mother from Balboa, Canal Zone, Jan. 21, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - mother from Balboa, Canal Zone, Jan. 22, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Em from Balboa, Canal Zone, Jan. 24, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - mother from Balboa, Canal Zone, Jan. 27, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Em from Balboa, Canal Zone, Jan. 28, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - family from Balboa, Canal Zone, Jan. 30, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Em from Balboa, Canal Zone, Feb. 3, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - mother from Balboa, Canal Zone, Feb. 6, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - parents from Balboa, Canal Zone, Feb. 9, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - parents, valentine from Balboa, Canal Zone, Feb. 10, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - mother from Denver, Colorado, March 2, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - father from Denver, Colorado, March 2, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - mother from Seattle, Washington, March 5, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - mother from Bremerton, Washington, March 6, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - father from Bremerton, Washington, March 6, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Em from Bremerton, Washington, March 7, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - father from Bremerton, Washington, March 9, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - mother from Bremerton, Washington, March 9, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - mother from Bremerton, Washington, March 10, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Em from Bremerton, Washington, March 12, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - mother from Bremerton, Washington, March 15, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - mother from Bremerton, Washington, March 17, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - mother from Bremerton, Washington, March 25, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - mother from Bremerton, Washington, April 2, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - mother from Bremerton, Washington, April 7, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Em from Bremerton, Washington, April 9, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - father from Bremerton, Washington, April 12, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Ens. John Andrews to Goyen's parents, April 13, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - regarding plans for Goyen's birthday (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - mother from Bremerton, Washington, April 15, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - mother from Bremerton, Washington, April 19, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - mother from Bremerton, Washington, April 21, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Em from Bremerton, Washington, April 29, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)